...the fastest fun in the west!
The Villain is a comedy, western film directed by Hal Needham.
Handsome Stranger has agreed to escort Charming Jones to
collect her inheritance from her father.
But Avery Simpson wants the money and hires notorious
outlaw Cactus Jack to ambush Charming.
However, Cactus Jack is not very good at robbing people.
Cactus Jack, played by Kirk Douglas.
Charming Jones, played by Ann-Margret.
Handsome Stranger, played by Arnold Schwarzenegger.
Nervous Elk, played by Paul Lynde.
Bank Clerk, played by Foster Brooks.
Damsel in Distress, played by Ruth Buzzi.
The Villain (released as Cactus Jack in the UK and Australia) is a 1979 American metrocolor Western comedy film directed by Hal Needham and starring Kirk Douglas,
Arnold Schwarzenegger, Ann-Margret, Paul Lynde (in his final film appearance), Foster Brooks, Strother Martin, Ruth Buzzi, Jack Elam, and Mel Tillis.
It is a parody of Western films, blended with an homage to the Warner Bros.
cartoon Wile E.
Coyote and the Road Runner.
The film explores themes of chase, train, explosion, glue, cowboy.
The tone is lighthearted.